uknetguide.co.uk 2019-05-24

# Cookie Policy

##  INTRODUCTION

UK Net Guide ([http://www.uknetguide.co.uk](http://www.uknetguide.co.uk/)) is owned and operated by Crystal Guides, a limited company registered in England. 

UK Net Guide considers Internet user privacy and data protection to be of paramount importance. Crystal Guides Ltd complies with the Data Protection Act 1998 in relation to all processing of personal data supplied to us by users and other personal data in our possession for any reason. We have registered with and notified the Data Protection Commissioner of our practice affecting personal data. 

This statement discloses the cookie and privacy policy for the UK Net Guide network of sites, which encompass the site [http://www.uknetguide.co.uk](http://www.uknetguide.co.uk/) and all co-branded versions of this site that collectively form and are referred to as the UK Net Guide network. This statement does not extend to sites that are linked to or which are not part of the UK Net Guide's network. See www.crystalguides.co.uk for a full list.

##  What is a Cookie?

Cookies are small text files which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on you computer's hard drive by your browser. They're used for many things, such as remembering whether you've visited the site before, and to help us work out how many new website visitors we get each month. They contain information about the use of your computer **but don't include personal information about you** (they don't store your name, for instance). 

You can read all about cookies here: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

##  About our Cookie Policy

Cookies do not damage your computer. Each web site can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a web site to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites.

The UK Net Guide network uses cookies to assign identification to your individual browser. This identifies your browser - but not you - to our servers every time you visit our network. Cookies by themselves cannot be used to find out the identity of any user. Unless you voluntarily advise us, the **UK Net Guide network will never know who you are, even though we assign your browser a cookie**. 

You can decide if you want to accept cookies by changing the settings on your browser to either accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set.

**The below links explain how you can control cookies via your web browser** \- remember that if you turn off cookies in your browser then these settings apply to all websites not just to UK Net Guide:

  * Internet Explorer <http://support.microsoft.com/kb/278835> (this page links to further information for different versions of IE - the mobile version is at <http://www.microsoft.com/windowsphone/en-us/howto/wp7/web/changing-privacy-and-other-browser-settings.aspx>
  * Chrome: [http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=95647](http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=95647)
  * Safari: <http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?path=Safari/5.0/en/9277.html> (or <http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1677> for mobile versions)
  * Firefox: <http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/Enabling%20and%20disabling%20cookies>
  * Blackberries: <http://docs.blackberry.com/en/smartphone_users/deliverables/32004/Turn_off_cookies_in_the_browser_60_1072866_11.jsp>
  * Android: [http://support.google.com/mobile/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=169022](http://support.google.com/mobile/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=169022)
  * Opera: <http://www.opera.com/browser/tutorials/security/privacy/>

The information gathered through the use of cookies, allows the UK Net Guide network to offer a quality Internet service and easily accessible online content to our users, and catalogue traffic patterns throughout the network in a manner that provides personal privacy protection. 

We also keep track of your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information about you, such as your location and your Internet Service Provider. The UK Net Guide network may also collect aggregate information on how our users are utilising the site. This might include information regarding traffic patterns through the sites. 

Other organisations that place advertising on our network also have the ability to assign a different cookie to your browser in a process that the UK Net Guide network does not control. Again, unless you voluntarily advise them, these advertisers will also never know who you are. 

##  What Cookies UK Net Guide Uses

  1. **Personalisation cookies**  
These cookies are used to recognise repeat visitors to the Website.
  2. **Analytics cookies**  
Monitor how visitors move around the Website and how they reached it. This is used so that we can see total (not individual) figures on which types of content users enjoy most, for instance.   
You can opt out of these if you want: Google: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>
  3. **Third-party service cookies**  
Social sharing, and other services are run by other companies. These companies may drop cookies on your computer when you use them on our site or if you are already logged in to them.  
Here is a list of places where you can find out more about specific services that we may use and their use of cookies:  

    * Facebook's data use policy: <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other>
    * AddThis (the service that runs some of our social sharing buttons): <http://www.addthis.com/privacy#.T6j--usS0bw>
    * Twitter's privacy policy: <https://twitter.com/privacy>
    * Google + see <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>
    * And Affiliate Networks, Some affiliate networks will cookie you so we can be credited with sales if you leave our site and then go on and buy goods and services. 
  4. **Our own ad serving and management cookies**  
We sell advertising space on UK Net Guide as we don't charge for content.  
As part of our advertising solution, we use several services that from time to time may help us and advertisers understand what adverts you might be interested in. These cookies hold information about the computer - they don't hold personal information about you (ie it's not linked to you as an individual). But they might hold a record of what other websites you've looked at - so we may show you a car advert if you've previously visited a motoring website.  
These are the services we use and how you can control those cookies. Please note that turning off advertising cookies won't mean that you are not served any advertising merely that it will not be tailored to your interests.  

    * Doubleclick (advertising): Privacy policy at <http://www.google.com/doubleclick/privacy/> and opt out via <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/>
    * Google Adsense (ad partner). Privacy policy at [https://support.google.com/adsense/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&utm_medium=link&gsessionid=DyXLmLB1J1MxXckh6tX6AQ&utm_campaign=ww-ww-et-asfe_&utm_source=aso&answer=48182](https://support.google.com/adsense/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&utm_medium=link&gsessionid=DyXLmLB1J1MxXckh6tX6AQ&utm_campaign=ww-ww-et-asfe_&utm_source=aso&answer=48182) and opt-out via <https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/>
    * Tribal Fusion: Privacy Policy at <http://exponential.com/privacy.html>
    * AOL: Privacy Policy at [http://privacy.aol.co.uk](http://privacy.aol.co.uk/)
    * Real Medai 24/7: Privacy Policy at <http://www.247realmedia.co.uk/EN-UK/privacy-policy.html>
    * Adjug: Privacy Policy at <http://www.adjug.com/info/privacy.asp>
    * Black Magic: Privacy Policy at <http://www.blackmagicmedia.co.uk/privacy.php>
    * Crimtan: Privacy Policy at <http://www.crimtan.com/privacy.html>
    * Criteo: Privacy Policy at <http://www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy>
    * Marimedia: Privacy Policy at <http://www.marimedia.net/?q=node/264>
    * Specific Media: Privacy Policy at <http://www.specificmedia.co.uk/privacy>
    * Addynamo: Privacy Policy at <http://www.addynamo.com/en/index.cfm?content=8233>

##  SHARING OF DATA

The UK Net Guide network will not disclose any of your personal information to a third party without your consent, unless we believe, in good faith, that the law requires it or that the rights or property of the UK Net Guide network need to be protected. 

##  LINKS TO OTHER SITES

The UK Net Guide network contains links to other sites not affiliated with the UK Net Guide network. These sites have their own cookie policies and practices with respect to online privacy, and the UK Net Guide network cannot be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these unaffiliated websites. 

In addition, in certain instances, a UK Net Guide advertiser may ask you for personal information. UK Net Guide cannot be held responsible for the privacy practices of its advertisers; however, UK Net Guide encourages our partners and advertisers to adopt privacy policies similar to our own. 

##  COMMENT

We suggest that you practice reasonable discretion with any site when providing site operators/owners with personal information. 

It should also be noted that whenever you post personal information in publicly accessible places, such as chat rooms or message boards, this information becomes available to anyone with access to the Internet. 

**For information about online behavioural advertising, about cookies, and about how to turn off behavioural adverts, please visit<http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/>**

Therefore, we recommend that you refrain from posting any information that you do not want seen in these public areas. You should feel free to contact any site that requests personal information from you if you have any questions regarding its policies.
